Finding Aid for Margaret Bayne Price Papers 1918-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Margaret Bayne Price Papers 1918-1969, 1947-1968
Price, Margaret Bayne, 1912-1968.
25 linear feet
Democratic National Committeewoman from Michigan, Vice-Chair of the Democratic National Committee and Director of Women's Affairs of the Democratic Party. Extensive correspondence, speeches, press releases, political campaign materials, newspaper clippings, agendas, and assorted printed material relating to her work in the Democratic Party; material concerning Democratic politics, 1948-1967, and the activities of the Democratic National Committee and the Michigan State Central Committee.
86104 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Hickman Price Jr. (donor no. 4711 ) and came to the library in 1969.
The collection is open for research.
Margaret Price was born in New York City, October 15, 1912. Active through most of her life in state and national Democratic Party affairs, Margaret Price (Mrs. Hickman Price) eventually came to serve as vice chair of the national Democratic Party (1960-1968). Although active civically as early as 1941-1942, when she served as chair of the YWCA World Emergency Fund, Price's involvement with the Democratic Party really began with her unsuccessful campaigns for Michigan auditor general in 1948 and 1950.
Her rise within the Democratic National Committee party machinery began with her work within the Michigan Democratic State Central Committee and her election in 1952 as national committeewoman from Michigan. She was subsequently re-elected in 1956 and 1960. She was later a founder and member of the party's advisory council (1956-1960), its executive committee (1956-1968), as well as serving as director of the party's women's activities (1960-1968) and as a member of its Campaign Conference for Democratic Women. In recognition of her service, Price was chair of the committee on permanent organization for the 1960 Democratic National Convention.
In addition, Price served on various governmental commissions and was especially involved in issues pertaining to women and children. She was chair of the Michigan Youth Commission, 1949-1956, attended the Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth in 1950, and was a member of the Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services.
The collection includes extensive correspondence, speeches, press releases, political campaign materials, newspaper clippings, agendas, and assorted printed material relating to her work in the Democratic Party; material concerning state and national Democratic politics, 1948-1967, and materials accumulated from her service with the Democratic National Committee and the Michigan State Central Committee.
The collection has been arranged into the following series: Correspondence; Press Materials; Speeches; Miscellaneous Materials; Organizational Activities; State and Local Politics; National Politics; Printed Materials; and Photographs.
Subjects:
Democratic National Committee (U.S.); Democratic National Convention (1952: Chicago); Democratic National Convention (1956: Chicago); Democratic National Convention (1960: Los Angeles); Democratic National Convention (1964: Atlantic City, N.J.); Democratic Party (Mich.); Democratic Party (Mich.). State Central Committee.; Democratic Party (U.S.). Advisory Council.; Elections--Michigan--1948.; Elections--Michigan--1950.; Elections--Michigan--1952.; Elections--Michigan--1954.; Elections--Michigan--1956.; Elections--Michigan--1958.; Elections--Michigan--1960.; Elections--Michigan--1962.; Elections--Michigan--1964.; Elections--Michigan--1966.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Michigan Youth Commission.; Presidents--United States--Election--1952.; Presidents--United States--Election--1956.; Presidents--United States--Election--1960.; Presidents--United States--Election--1964.; Price, Margaret Bayne, 1912-1968.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1948.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1950.; United States. Congress--Elections, 1952.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; Women in politics--Michigan.; Women in politics--United States.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Democratic National Committee (U.S.); Democratic Party (U.S.); Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Jackson, Henry M. (Henry Martin), 1912-1983.; Johnson, Lady Bird, 1912-2007.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994; Political elections.; Politics and government--1961-1970.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; United States. Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services.; Women--Political life.
Contributors:
Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Aiken, Paul C., 1910-1974; Albert, Carl Bert, 1908-2000; Anderson, Clinton Presba, 1895-1975; Anderson, Eugenie, 1900-; Bailey, John Moran, 1904-1975.; Ball, George W., 1909-; Bayh, Birch, 1928-; Bentley, Alvin M. (Alvin Morell), 1918-1969.; Berthelot, Helen W.; Bible, Alan, 1909-1988; Boggs, Thomas Hale, 1914-; Bowles, Chester, 1901-1986.; Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-1996.; Bunker, Ellsworth, 1894-1984; Butler, Paul M. (Paul Mulholland), 1905-1961.; Cannon, Clarence, 1879-1964.; Cavanagh, Jerome Patrick, 1928-1979.; Celebrezze, Anthony J. (Anthony Joseph), 1910-1998; Church, Frank.; Clark, Joseph S.; Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon), 1897-1978.; Clevenger, Raymond Francis, 1926-; Cohen, Wilbur J. (Wilbur Joseph), 1913-1987.; Collins, John J. (John Joseph), 1935-; Collins, LeRoy.; Connolly, John W.; Daley, Richard J., 1902-1976.; Dempsey, John N., 1915-; Diggs, Charles C.; Dillon, C. Douglas (Clarence Douglas), 1909-2003; DiSalle, Michael V. (Michael Vincent), 1908-1981; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976; Doyle, William F.; Duke, Angier Biddle, 1915-1995; Dunnigan, James P.; Edwards, India.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Farrell, Lawrence Llewellyn, 1903-1971.; Faubus, Orval Eugene, 1910-1994; Ferency, Zolton A., 1922-1993; Fowler, Henry H., 1908-2000; Freeman, Orville L.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Gore, Albert, 1907-1998.; Griffiths, Hicks G., 1910-; Griffiths, Martha W. (Martha Wright), 1912-2003.; Gronouski, John A. (John Austin), 1919-1996; Gruening, Ernest, 1887-1974.; Hannah, John A., 1902-1991; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986.; Harris, Fred R., 1930-; Hart, Adelaide, 1900-; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Hartke, Vance.; Hayden, Carl Trumbull, 1877-1972.; Hill, Lister, 1894-1984; Hobby, Oveta Culp, 1905-1995; Hodges, Luther Hartwell, 1898-1974.; Holland, Spessard L. (Spessard Lindsey), 1892-1971.; Hughes, Richard J. (Richard Joseph), 1909-1992; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Brown, Muriel Buck Humphrey.; Jackson, Henry M. (Henry Martin), 1912-1983.; Jeffrey, Mildred, 1911-2004.; Jenkins, Walter.; Johnson, Lady Bird, 1912-2007.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Katzenbach, Nicholas deB. (Nicholas deBelleville), 1922-2012; Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963.; Kefauver, Nancy Patterson.; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009; Kennedy, Ethel, 1928-; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Kerner, Otto, 1908-1976.; Kerr, Robert S. (Robert Samuel), 1896-1963.; Lacy, Ernest J.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lesinski, John, 1914-; Lippmann, Walter, 1889-1974.; Long, Russell B.; Lorch, Emil, 1870-1963.; Louchheim, Katie, 1903-1991; McCormack, John W., 1891-1980.; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012; McIntyre, Thomas J., 1915-; McKeithen, John J. (John Julian), 1918-1999; McKellar, Kenneth Douglas, 1869-1957.; McKinney, Frank Edward, 1904-1974.; McNamara, Patrick Vincent, 1894-1966.; McNamara, Robert S., 1916-2009; Magnuson, Warren G. (Warren Grant), 1905-1989; Mansfield, Mike, 1903-2001; Mayo, Leonard W.; Mesta, Perle.; Mitchell, Stephen A. (Stephen Arnold), 1903-1974; Monroney, Mike, 1902-; Montoya, Joseph Manuel, 1915-1978; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974.; Moyers, Bill D.; Muskie, Edmund S., 1914-1996; Neuberger, Maurine B. (Maurine Brown), 1907-2000; O'Brien, Lawrence Francis.; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994; Peabody, Endicott, 1920-1997; Peck, Gregory, 1916-; Powell, Adam Clayton, 1908-1972.; Proxmire, William.; Quimby, Thomas H. E. (Thomas Howard Emerson), 1918-1998; Rayburn, Sam, 1882-1961.; Reuther, Roy L., d. 1968.; Reuther, Victor G. (Victor George), 1912-2004; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970.; Ribicoff, Abraham, 1910-1998; Roberts, Dennis Joseph, 1903-1994; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Roosevelt, Elliott, 1910-1990; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1914-1988.; Roosevelt, James, 1907-1991; Rusk, Dean, 1909-1994; Salinger, Pierre.; Sallade, George Wahr, 1922-; Sanford, Terry, 1917-1998; Scholle, August, 1904-; Smathers, George A. (George Armistead), 1913-2007; Sorenson, Theodore C.; Sparkman, John, 1899-1985.; Staebler, Burnette.; Staebler, Neil, 1905-2000; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Swainson, John B. (John Burley), 1925-1994.; Symington, Stuart, 1901-1988; Talmadge, Herman E. (Herman Eugene), 1913-2002.; Todd, Paul Harold, 1921-2008; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tydings, Joseph Davies, 1928-; Tyroler, Charles.; Udall, Stewart L.; Vivian, Weston Edward, 1924-; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1910-1991.; Weaver, Robert C. (Robert Clifton), 1907-1997; Williams, G. Mennen, 1911-1988.; Williams, G. Mennen, Mrs.; Williams, Harrison A.; Wirtz, Willard, 1912-2010; Yarborough, Ralph Webster, 1903-1996; Youngdahl, Luther W., 1896-1978
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1918, 1921-1923, 1926-1927 (Box 1)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - 1942, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
  - 1947-August 1952, 23 folders (Box 1)
  - September 1952-September 1954, 21 folders (Box 2)
  - October 1954-1958, 19 folders (Box 3)
  - 1959-1962, 19 folders (Box 4)
  - 1963-1964, 20 folders (Box 5)
  - 1965, 19 folders (Box 6)
  - 1966-June 1967, 25 folders (Box 7)
  - July 1967-1969 undated, 19 folders (Box 8)
- Press Materials
  - For and About Women, Capital Capsule, 1955-1958 (Box 8)
  - Press releases
    - Democratic National Committee July 1952-November 1966, 9 folders (Box 8)
    - Democratic National Committee 1967, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - White House January 1961-November 1967 (Box 9)
    - Editors News Service April 1965-June 1967 (Box 9)
    - Democratic Advisory Council October 1957-April 1959 (Box 9)
    - Operation Support for Johnson/Humphrey, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Campaign Bulletin no. 1 (Kennedy/ Johnson) August 26, 1960; also Correction Please, September 14, 1960, September 14, 1960 (Box 9)
    - Lady Bird Special October 1964 (Box 9)
    - Operation Support for the Great Society June 1966-January 1967 (Box 9)
    - 1965 Presidential Inaugural Committee November 1964-January 1965 (Box 9)
    - United Nations January-April 1952 (Box 9)
    - Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services April 1963-April 1968 (Box 9)
    - Various national groups 1962-1966 (Box 9)
    - Campaign Conference for Democratic Women 1960 (Box 9)
    - 1962-1967 of departments within the federal government (Box 9)
    - July-December 1960 Washington reports of Senator John F. Kennedy (Box 9)
    - August-September 1952 Senator Blair Moody (Box 9)
    - September 1952 Michigan speeches of Governor Adlai E. Stevenson (Box 9)
    - 1952-1967 Michigan Democratic State Central Committee (Box 9)
    - June-July 1948 Washtenaw Democratic Club (Box 9)
    - September-October 1964, July 1965 Pennsylvania State Democratic Central Committee (Box 9)
    - December 1950 Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous statewide party organizations (Box 9)
  - Newsletters
    - Democratic Women's Club of Dade County, Florida September 1966-January 1967 (Box 9)
    - Fairbanks Women's Democratic Club Newsletter, April 1965-June 1966 (Box 9)
    - Kandid: Kansas Democratic Information Digest, May 1965-February 1967 (Box 9)
    - The Michigan Democrat April 1948-March 1966 (Box 9)
      (removed to library's printed section, except for miscellaneous newsletters)
    - Donkey Bulletin [Missoula County, Montana], February 1965-September 1966 (Box 9)
    - Pennsylvania Democratic News, May 1965-March 1966 (Box 9)
    - Donkey Serenade [Pomona Valley, California], April 1965-October 1966 (Box 9)
    - Donkey Serenade [Seminole County, Oklahoma], March 1966-March 1967 (Box 9)
    - South Dakota Democratic News, undated (Box 9)
    - Washtenaw Democratic Club Bulletin and Washtenaw Democrat, 1948-September 1952 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters [A-M] (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters [N-Z] (Box 9)
    - Political press materials (Box 9)
    - Y.A.C. News, November/December 1954-April 1956 (Box 9)
  - Other press materials
    - Miscellaneous newsletters of youth commissions [A-Z] (Box 9)
    - Press materials of various organizations (Box 9)
    - Articles by Margaret Price (Box 9)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - Undated (Box 10)
    - The Island News, Mackinac Island, Michigan, July 1945-September 1949 (Box 10)
    - 1954 concerning the Lapeer Case (Box 10)
    - 1939-1948 (Box 10)
    - 1949 (Box 10)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 10)
    - 1952 (Box 10)
    - 1952 concerning Democratic National Convention, Chicago, 3 folders (Box 10)
    - 1953 (Box 10)
    - 1954 (Box 10)
    - 1955 (Box 10)
    - 1956 (Box 10)
    - 1956 concerning Democratic National Convention, Chicago (Box 10)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 10)
    - 1959 (Box 10)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 10)
    - 1960 concerning Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 10)
    - 1962 concerning Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 10)
    - 1962 (Box 10)
    - 1963 (Box 10)
    - 1964 (Box 11)
    - October 1964 concerning 1964 Campaign (Box 11)
    - Newspapers concerning1964 Campaign (Box 11)
    - 1965 (Box 11)
    - 1966 (Box 11)
    - 1967 (Box 11)
    - 1968 (Box 11)
    - The Brazil Herald, 1961 (Box 11)
    - 1949-1965 (unsorted) (Box 11)
    - 1962-1966 (unsorted) (Box 11)
    - 1964 (unsorted) (Box 11)
- Speeches
  - 1950-1965 [A-C] (Box 11)
  - 1948-1966 [D-I] (Box 11)
  - 1954-1967 [J-L] (Box 11)
  - 1950-1965 [M-Price, H.] (Box 11)
  - Undated [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1940-1955 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1956-1959 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1960 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1961 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1962 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1962 [Margaret Price]; include Operation Support scripts (Box 12)
  - 1963 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1964 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - January-April 1965 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - May-December 1965 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1966 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - January-June 1967, undated [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - July-December 1967 [Margaret Price] (Box 12)
  - 1952-1967 [R-Wh] (Box 12)
  - 1950-1964 [Wi-Z] (Box 12)
  - Undated [Margaret Price and others (fragmentary)] (Box 12)
  - Undated [Margaret Price and others (fragmentary)], 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Speech materials 1952 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous speeches 1948-1968 (Box 13)
- Miscellaneous materials
  - Schedules and itineraries undated, 1948-1967, 17 folders (Box 13)
  - Minutes of meetings 1948-1951, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Minutes of meetings 1952-1966, 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Biographies
    - [A-D] (Box 14)
    - [E-H] (Box 14)
    - [I-M] (Box 14)
    - [N-P] (Box 14)
    - [Margaret Price] (Box 14)
    - [Q-Z[ (Box 14)
    - Group biographies (Box 14)
  - 1921-1938 and undated; include childhood writings (Box 14)
- Organizational activities
  - YWCA World Emergency Fund 1940-1941, undated (Box 14)
  - UNICEF 1951-1954, undated (Box 14)
  - Ann Arbor Community Chest financial reports 1948-1950 (Box 14)
  - Ann Arbor Community Chest reports 1947-1950 and undated; also membership lists, 1948-1953 (Box 14)
  - Ann Arbor Council of Social Agencies 1946-1949, undated (Box 14)
  - Various charitable organizations 1948, undated (Box 14)
  - Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth 1950, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth 1950 (Box 15)
  - National Midcentury Committee for Children and Youth, Inc. 1952-1954 (Box 15)
  - Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth Advisory Council on State and Local Action 1949-1955, undated (Box 15)
  - Federal Interdepartmental Committee on Children and Youth 1949-1955, undated (Box 15)
  - Various children and youth organizations undated (Box 15)
  - Joint Conference on Children and Youth 1955 (Box 15)
  - Children and Youth Conferences pamphlets undated (Box 15)
  - Labor statistics for youth conferences papers 1950 (Box 15)
  - Michigan Youth Commission
    - Membership lists undated (Box 15)
    - Reports to the Governor undated (Box 15)
    - Pamphlets and publicity undated (Box 15)
    - Miscellanea of the Michigan Youth Commission Youth Advisory Council undated (Box 15)
    - Reports 1949-1955 (Box 15)
    - Reports undated (Box 15)
    - Reports undated (Box 15)
    - Miscellanea undated (Box 15)
    - East Lansing meeting of the Michigan Youth Commission undated (Box 15)
  - White House Conference on Education 1955 (Box 16)
  - Mackinac Island State Park Commission undated (Box 16)
  - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations 1954-1955 (Box 16)
  - Associaco Universitria Interamericana 1962-1967, 6 folders (Box 16)
  - Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services 1958-1968, 8 folders (Box 16)
- State and local politics
  - Michigan Democratic State Central Committee
    - Papers 1949-1956 include county files (Box 17)
    - Papers 1949-1956 include county files (Box 18)
  - Ann Arbor/Washtenaw County campaigns
    - Ann Arbor politics 1948-1952, undated (Box 18)
    - Washtenaw County politics 1950 include census-enumerator material (Box 18)
    - Washtenaw County Democratic Conventions 1948-1953, undated (Box 18)
    - Slosson Congressional Campaign 1948 (Box 18)
    - John Dawson Congressional Campaign 1950 (Box 18)
    - Washtenaw County Democratic Club 1948, undated (Box 18)
    - Washtenaw County Democratic Club committees Membership lists 1948-1953 (Box 18)
    - Washtenaw County Democratic Club 1948-1953 (Box 18)
  - State Democratic Party
    - Michigan State Democratic Party 1948-1953, 5 folders (Box 18)
    - Michigan State Democratic Party notebook 1954 (Box 18)
    - Michigan State Democratic Party 1955 (Box 18)
    - Michigan State Democratic Party 1956-1961, undated, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Michigan State Democratic Party fact sheets 1953-1954 (Box 19)
    - Auditor General campaigns 1948, 1950 (Box 19)
- National Politics
  - Democratic National Committee
    - 1948-1951 (Box 19)
    - 1952 (Box 19)
    - 1952 Stevenson campaign (Box 19)
    - 1953 (Box 19)
    - 1954 (Box 19)
    - 1955, 1 notebook; 1 folder (Box 19)
    - 1956 (Box 19)
    - 1956 Stevenson campaign (Box 19)
    - 1957-1959 (Box 19)
    - 1960, 1 notebook (Box 19)
    - 1960-1961 include 1960 election background and strategy memoranda (Box 19)
    - Democratic Digest, undated (Box 19)
    - Undated (Box 19)
    - Political notebooks 1948-1960 (Box 19)
    - Democratic Advisory Council 1956-1958 (Box 19)
    - 1960-1962 include Price acceptance of vice-chairmanship (Box 20)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 20)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 20)
    - undated (Box 20)
  - Women's Activities of the Democratic National Committee
    - 1948-1968 undated, 4 folders (Box 20)
    - Undated; also, 1960 Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 20)
    - Undated; also, 1962 Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 20)
    - Undated; also, 1964 Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 20)
    - Undated; also, 1966 Campaign Conference for Democratic Women, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Undated; also, 1968 Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 21)
  - Democratic National Committee Programs
    - Strategy for Peace 1960-1961 (Box 21)
    - Operation Support 1962-1964 (Box 21)
    - Operation Know-How 1962 (Box 21)
    - Project Head Start 1964-1965 (Box 21)
    - Tell-a-Friend 1964 (Box 21)
    - Coffee with the First Lady 1964 (Box 21)
    - Wider View--Vistas in an Expanding World 1966 (Box 21)
  - Conventions and campaigns
    - Democratic National Convention 1968 Site Committee 1967 (Box 21)
    - 1960 Democratic National Convention (Box 21)
    - 1960 Kennedy Presidential Campaign (Box 21)
    - 1960 presidential campaign-general (Box 21)
    - 1962 election campaign; include briefing books, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - 1964 Democratic National Convention (Box 21)
    - 1964 presidential campaign; include Flying Caravans (Box 22)
    - 1964 presidential campaign, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - President Johnson inauguration 1965, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - 1966 election campaign (Box 22)
  - Campaign materials [arranged by name of candidate]
    - Alben Barkley and A.B. Chandler (Box 22)
    - William O. Douglas and Charles C. Diggs, etc. (Box 22)
    - Martha Griffiths, Philip A. Hart, and Hubert Humphrey, etc. (Box 22)
    - Lyndon Johnson, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Estes Kefauver and Harry Kelly (Box 22)
    - John F. Kennedy (Box 22)
    - Robert S. Kerr (Box 22)
    - Patrick V. McNamara and Blair Moody (Box 23)
    - Richard Russell and Neil Staebler (Box 23)
    - Adlai Stevenson, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Harry Truman (Box 23)
    - G. Mennen Williams (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous campaign materials 1948-1967 (Box 23)
    - Margaret Price (Box 23)
    - Miscellanea 1944-1967 (Box 23)
- Printed materials
  - 1950 White Conference on Youth, etc. 1950 (Box 24)
  - Democratic politics (Box 25)
- Photographs
  - Portraits, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Informal photos and with husband and family (Box 25)
  - Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services (Box 25)
  - With Democratic party personalities (Box 25)
  - Political meetings (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
Selected Index to Correspondence
Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.
July 22, 1958
Aiken, Paul C., 1910-
Dec. 16, 1964
Albert, Carl Bert, 1908-
Apr. 11, 1962
Anderson, Clinton Presba, 1895-
Jan. 29, 1964, Feb. 3, 1964, Jan. 11, 1965
Anderson, Eugenie, 1900-
Dec. 23, 1952, Apr. 1962, Sept. 23, 1965, Oct. 5, 1965
Bailey, John Moran, 1904-1975.
1961-1967
Ball, George W., 1909-
Aug. 7, 1963
Bayh, Birch, 1928-
Dec. 24, 1964, Dec. 30, 1964, Aug. 18, 1965, Dec. 14, 1965, Feb. 17, 1966, Feb. 21, 1966, Mar. 22, 1966
Bentley, Alvin M. (Alvin Morell), 1918-1969.
July 11, 1955
Berthelot, Helen W.
1952, Jan. 21, 1953, Apr. 16, 1953, Oct. 19, 1954, Dec. 8, 1954, May 4, 1955, June 22, 1956, Oct. 18, 1956, Nov. 21, 1956, May 6, 1957, Nov. 17, 1957, Mar. 1, 1959, Mar. 11, 1959, June 27, 1962, 1964-1965
Bible, Alan, 1909-
Apr. 3, 1962
Boggs, Thomas Hale, 1914-
Apr. 11, 1962, Mar. 11, 1964
Bowles, Chester, 1901-
Jan. 27, 1954
Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-
Apr. 3, 1962
Bunker, Ellsworth, 1894-
July 16, 1964
Butler, Paul M. (Paul Mulholland), 1905-1961.
1954-1957, Feb. 21, 1958, Oct. 20, 1958, 1959, Jan. 27, 1960, June 29, 1960, July 8, 1960
Cannon, Clarence, 1879-1964.
Aug. 16, 1956, May 7, 1962, May 9, 1962, Mar. 12, 1964
Cavanagh, Jerome Patrick, 1928-1979.
Jan. 8, 1963
Celebrezze, Anthony J., 1910-
Mar. 24, 1964
Church, Frank.
May 19, 1965
Clark, Joseph S.
Mar. 2, 1965, June 16, 1965, June 21, 1965
Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon), 1897-1978.
Aug. 23, 1950
Clevenger, Raymond Francis, 1926-
Sept. 7, 1965
Cohen, Wilbur J. (Wilbur Joseph), 1913-1987.
Feb. 5, 1961, June 3, 1963, June 11, 1963, July 17, 1963, June 8, 1965
Collins, John J. (John Joseph), 1935-
May 6, 1961, Sept. 8, 1961, June 25, 1962
Collins, LeRoy.
Aug. 29, 1960, Aug. 31, 1960
Connolly, John W.